Jonathan Krause Rare Newspaper and Magazine Collection 1648-1881 E302.1 .J76 E302.1 .J76
Lilly Library
- Colonial American and Early Republic Individuals
  - Alexander Hamilton
    - H.G. LETTER IX, New York Daily Advertiser, March 23, 1789 (Item 148)
    - H.G. LETTER X, New York Daily Advertiser, March 25, 1789 (Item 149)
    - H.G. LETTER XI, New York Daily Advertiser, March 27, 1789 (Item 150)
    - H.G. LETTER XII, New York Daily Advertiser, March 28, 1789 (Item 151)
    - H.G. LETTER XIII, New York Daily Advertiser, March 31, 1789 (Item 152)
    - H.G. LETTER XV, New York Daily Advertiser, April 8, 1789 (Item 153)
    - H.G. LETTER XVI, New York Daily Advertiser, April 11, 1789 (Item 154)
    - REPORT ON THE PUBLIC CREDIT, Gazette of the United States, January 20, 27, 1790 (Item 155)
      First mention and excerpts from one of the great state papers in American history.
    - TREASURY REPORT REGARDING PAYMENT OF STATE DEBTS, Gazette of the United States, March 6, 1790 (Item 156)
    - REPORT ON THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A MINT, Universal Asylum, and Columbian Magazine, March, April, 1791; Size: Small (Item 157)
      One of the great state papers in American history.
      Includes Thomas Paine 487 (April)
    - LETTER TO BOSTON BOARD OF ASSESSORS, Columbian Centinel, August 20, 1791 (Item 158)
    - SOCIETY FOR THE ENCOURAGEMENT OF USEFUL MANUFACTURES (SUM), National Gazette, December 8, 1791, July 18, 21, October 10, 1792 (Item 159)
      Hamilton's idea for an industrial park and beginning of independent America.
      See French Revolution 937 and French Revolution 942
    - REPORT ON MANUFACTURES, American Museum Magazine, January 1792; Size: Small (Item 160)
    - T.L. LETTER I, Gazette of the United States, July 25, 1792 (Item 161)
      Beginning of newspaper war with Jefferson.
    - T.L. LETTER II, Gazette of the United States, August 1, 1792 (Item 163)
    - DETECTOR, Gazette of the United States, July 28, 1792 (Item 162)
      Attributed to Hamilton by Philip Marsh.
    - PHILLIP FRENEAU AFFIDAVIT RESPONDING TO CHARGES BY HAMILTON OF JEFFERSON'S UNDUE INFLUENCE, Gazette of the United States, August 8, 1792 (Item 164)
    - AN AMERICAN ESSAY II ESSAY ATTACKING JEFFERSON, Columbian Centinel, August 25, 1792 (Item 165)
    - CATULLUS I, Columbian Centinel, October 13, 1792 (Item 166)
      Attacking Jefferson.
    - CATULLUS IV, Gazette of the United States, October 17, 1792 (Item 167)
    - CATULLUS V, American Daily Advertiser, November 26, 1792 (Item 169)
      Listed as IV.
    - CATULLUS VI, Gazette of the United States, December 22, 1792 (Item 171)
      Includes Thomas Paine 498
    - AMERICANUS, Gazette of the United States, October 20, 1792 (Item 168)
    - REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY RESPECTING THE REDEMPTION OF THE PUBLIC DEBT, ETC., Gazette of the United States, December 12, 1792 (Item 170)
    - REPORT ON THE BALANCE OF UNAPPROPRIATED REVENUE RESPONDING TO GILES RESOLUTIONS, Gazette of the United States, February 9, 1793 (Item 172)
    - DEFENSE BEFORE THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Columbian Centinel, February 20, 1793 (Item 173)
    - DEFENSE BEFORE THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, National Gazette, March 9, 1793 (Item 174)
    - PACIFICUS I, Columbian Centinel, July 20, 1793 (Item 182)
      The Pacificus-Helvidius (Hamilton-Madison) debate is the most famous and significant constitutional debate in American history.
      Includes Toussaint Louverture 411 (July 20)
    - PACIFICUS II, Gazette of the United States, July 3, 1793 (Item 175)
    - PACIFICUS II, Columbian Centinel, July 24, 1793 (Item 183)
      Includes Toussaint Louverture 411 (July 24)
    - PACIFICUS III, Gazette of the United States, July 6, 1793 (Item 176)
    - PACIFICUS III, Columbian Centinel, July 27, 1793 (Item 184)
    - PACIFICUS IV, Gazette of the United States, July 10, 1793 (Item 177)
      2 copies. Includes Toussaint 409
    - PACIFICUS V, Gazette of the United States, July 13, 17, 1793 (Item 178)
    - PACIFICUS V, American Daily Advertiser, July 19, 1793 (Item 180)
      Includes Hamilton 181 and Toussaint Louverture 36 (July 19)
    - PACIFICUS VI, Gazette of the United States, July 17, 1793 (Item 179)
    - PACIFICUS VI, American Daily Advertiser, July 19, 1793 (Item 181)
      See: Alexander Hamilton 180
    - PACIFICUS VI, Columbian Centinel, August 10, 1793 (Item 190)
    - PACIFICUS VII, Gazette of the United States, July 27, 1793 (Item 185)
      Includes Toussaint Louverture 409 and Toussaint Louverture 412
    - PACIFICUS VII, American Daily Advertiser, July 29, 1793 (Item 186)
      Includes Toussaint Louverture 410 (July 29)
    - NO JACOBIN I, American Daily Advertiser, July 31, 1793 (Item 187)
      Attacking French Revolution and Jeffersonian attitudes.
    - NO JACOBIN II, American Daily Advertiser, August 5, 1793 (Item 188)
    - NO JACOBIN III, American Daily Advertiser, August 8, 1793 (Item 189)
    - NO JACOBIN IX, Gazette of the United States, August 31, 1793 (Item 191)
      See: James Madison 448
    - LETTER DEFENDING ALEXANDER STEVENS, Gazette of United States, September 14, 1793 (Item 192)
      See: James Madison 450
    - AMERICANUS I, Gazette of the United States, February 1, 1794 (Item 193)
      Hamilton's final response to Madison.
    - AMERICANUS II, Gazette of the United States, February 8, 1794 (Item 194)
      Continues attack on Madison and Jefferson.
    - TULLY I, American Daily Advertiser, August 23, 1794 (Item 195)
      On Whisky Rebellion and Constitution.
      Includes Whiskey Rebellion 671
    - TULLY III, American Daily Advertiser, August 28, 1794 (Item 196)
    - TULLY IV, American Daily Advertiser, September 2, 1794 (Item 197)
      On Whisky Rebellion and attacks on Congress.
    - THE DEFENSE (CAMILLUS) No. IV, Connecticut Courant, August 31, 1795 (Item 198)
      On Jay Treaty.
    - THE EXPLANATION (Part One), Providence Gazette, December 5, 1795 (Item 199)
      Defending Washington and self on corruption charges.
    - THE EXPLANATION (Part Two), Massachusetts Spy, December 16, 1795 (Item 200)
      Includes George Washington 596
    - PHOCION I, Gazette of the United States, October 14, 1796 (Item 201)
      The Phocions were Anti-Jefferson essays on the eve of 1796 election.
      Comments from Mr. Krause: I originally acquired the Phocions because of Ron Chernow's attribution to Hamilton. After extensive research and discussion with scholars, I have concluded that the consensus of his contemporaries that attributed the Phocion essays to William Loughton Smith is "probably" correct, although some historical and stylistic problems remain. Chernow's attribution to Hamilton, seconded by historian John Ferling (predicated on Chernow's attribution), probably rested on a false premise. Since Hamilton had used the Phocion pseudonym in two 1784 essays, when Chernow found the 1796 Phocions on a visit to the New York Historical Society, he and or the historical society confused them, believing the 1784 pseudonym of Hamilton was also used by him on the 1796 essays. I talked with the New York Historical Society, and they have a catalog entry with William Loughton Smith as the author of the 1796 Phocions. The prolific production of twenty- five essays in five weeks, the mastery of economic detail (although Smith may have had help from Oliver Wolcott Jr., who succeeded Hamilton as Treasury Secretary), plus the Beckley letter to Madison on October 15, 1796, where he attributes Phocion to Hamilton, could easily lead one to Hamilton. Hamilton may still have written them, and for political reasons (such as wanting to run for president in the future), allowed-instructed Smith to take the credit. Smith was a congressman, colleague, and friend of Hamilton, who pushed Hamilton's agenda vigorously in Congress. At this point, authorship is an open question, although the evidence leans toward Smith. Smith published "The Pretensions of Thomas Jefferson to the Presidency Examined" in 1796, supposedly a compilation of the Phocion essays published in the Gazette of the United States. (Regardless of who is the author, these essays may well have played a part in the 1796 election victory of Adams over Jefferson, which was the intention of the essays.)
    - PHOCION XVII, Gazette of the United States, November 8, 1796 (Item 995)
    - PHOCION XIX, Gazette of the United States, November 10, 1796 (Item 996)
    - PHOCION XX, Gazette of the United States, November 11, 1796 (Item 997)
    - PHOCION XXIII, Gazette of the United States, November 16, 1796 (Item 202)
    - PHOCION XXIV, Gazette of the United States, November 19, 1796 (Item 203)
    - LETTER ON REYNOLD'S AFFAIR, Gazette of the United States, July 8, 1797 (Item 204)
    - LETTER ON AURORA LIBELS AND FREE PRESS, Connecticut Courant, November 18, 1799 (Item 205)
    - LETTER FROM ALEXANDER HAMILTON CONCERNING THE PUBLIC CONDUCT AND CHARACTER OF JOHN ADAMS, ESQUIRE, PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES, Philadelphia Aurora, October 22, 1800 (Item 206)
      Intercepted by Aaron Burr and released to the Republican press (the Aurora) before Hamilton could publish it in pamphlet form. It proved to be a catalyst for Jefferson's victory in the 1800 election and the beginning of the end of Hamilton's career and the Federalist party.
    - ADDRESS TO ELECTORS OF NEW YORK, The Portfolio, May 23, 30, June 6, 1801; Size: Small (Item 207)
    - The EXAMINATION I, The Balance, January 5, 1802; Size: Small (Item 208)
      Attacking the Jefferson administration and Hamilton's final defense and review of the Constitution and his own record.
    - THE EXAMINATION II, The Balance, January 12, 1802; Size: Small (Item 209)
    - THE EXAMINATION III, The Balance, January 19, 1802; Size: Small (Item 210)
    - THE EXAMINATION IV, The Balance, January 26, 1802; Size: Small (Item 211)
    - THE EXAMINATION V, The Balance, February 2, 1802; Size: Small (Item 212)
    - THE EXAMINATION VI, The Balance, February 9, 1802; Size: Small (Item 213)
    - THE EXAMINATION VII, The Balance, February 16, 1802; Size: Small (Item 214)
    - THE EXAMINATION VIII, The Balance, February 23, 1802; Size: Small (Item 215)
    - THE EXAMINATION IX, The Balance, March 2, 1802; Size: Small (Item 218)
    - THE EXAMINATION X, The Balance, March 9, 1802; Size: Small (Item 221)
    - THE EXAMINATION XI, The Balance, March 16, 23, 1802; Size: Small (Item 222)
    - THE EXAMINATION XII, New York Evening Post, February 23, 1802 (Item 216)
    - THE EXAMINATION XIII, New York Evening Post, February 27, 1802 (Item 217)
    - THE EXAMINATION XIV, New York Evening Post, March 2, 1802 (Item 219)
    - THE EXAMINATION XV, New York Evening Post, March 3, 1802 (Item 220)
    - THE EXAMINATION XVI, New York Evening Post, March 19, 1802 (Item 223)
    - THE EXAMINATION XVII, New York Evening Post, March 20, 1802 (Item 224)
    - THE EXAMINATION XVIII, New York Evening Post, April 8, 1802 (Item 225)
    - LETTER REFUTING CHARGE WASHINGTON AND LAFAYETTE ORDERED HAMILTON TO MURDER PRISONERS AT YORKTOWN, The Balance, August 17, 1802; Size: Small (Item 226)
    - DEATH AND FUNERAL AND HAMILTON/BURR CORRESPONDENCE, The Repertory, July 20, 1804 (Item 227)
      Includes Aaron Burr 58
  - John Hancock
    - SPEECH ON JUST COMPLETED CONSTITUTION AND RATIFICATION AND SHAYS' REBELLION, Massachusetts Gazette, October 19, 1787 (Item 228)
      See: John Adams 1
  - Patrick Henry
    - SENEX OPPOSING ADAM'S DEFENSE OF CONSTITUTIONS OF GOVERNMENT, Salem Mercury, September 4, 1787 (Item 229)
      Includes Constitution 637
  - John Jay
    - FEDERALIST NO. 2, American Museum Magazine, November 1787; Size: Small (Item 230)
      First appearance in an American magazine
      See: Alexander Hamilton 133
    - FEDERALIST NO. 3, American Museum Magazine, December 1787; Size: Small (Item 231)
    - FEDERALIST NO. 4, American Museum Magazine, December 1787; Size: Small (Item 232)
    - FEDERALIST NO. 5, American Museum Magazine, December 1787; Size: Small (Item 233)
    - EXCHANGE OF LETTERS WITH LORD GRENVILLE, Federal Orrery, October 30, 1794 (Item 234)
    - TWO LETTERS, Massachusetts Spy, November 16, 1796 (Item 235)
      Includes French Revolution 954
  - Thomas Jefferson
    - INAUGURAL ADDRESS, Columbian Centinel, March 14, 1801 (Item 252)
    - INAUGURAL ADDRESS, Boston Gazette, March 16, 1801 (Item 253)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Boston Gazette, December 27, 1802 (Item 273)
      Includes Thomas Jefferson 274
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Farmer's Museum, December 28, 1802 (Item 275)
      See: Thomas Paine 514
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, The Balance, December 28, 1802; Size: Small (Item 276)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, The Balance, October 25, 1803; Size: Small (Item 283)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, New York Evening Post, November 12, 1804 (Item 286)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, The Repertory, November 20, 1804 (Item 287)
    - SECOND INAUGURAL ADDRESS, The Balance, March 19, 1805; Size: Small (Item 288)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Boston Gazette, December 12, 1805 (Item 289)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, The Balance, December 17, 1805; Size: Small (Item 290)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE AND PROCLAMATION AGAINST BURR CONSPIRACY, The Balance, December 9, 1806; Size: Small (Item 291)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, New York Herald, October 31, 1807 (Item 293)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, Charleston Courier, November 9, 1807 (Item 294)
    - STATE OF THE UNION MESSAGE, The Balance, November 15, 1808; Size: Small (Item 300)
    - INSTRUCTIONS FOR VIRGINIA DELEGATES TO CONGRESS, London Chronicle, September 24, 1774; Size: Small (Item 236)
      On the eve of the first Continental Congress, the concluding part of Jefferson's first significant political writing, an early unpublished and shortened version of A Summary View. Found nowhere else except the Library of Congress. Earliest reference to a Jefferson writing.
    - A SUMMARY VIEW OF THE RIGHTS OF BRITISH AMERICA, London Chronicle, November 24, 1774; Size: Small (Item 237)
      Conclusion of Jefferson's first published opus, a founding document of America, and a precursor of Declaration of Causes and Declaration of Independence. One of first public mentions of Jefferson. First and maybe only excerpts of A Summmary View in a paper.
    - DECLARATION OF CAUSES AND NECESSITY OF TAKING UP ARMS, Gentleman's Magazine, August 1775; Size: Small (Item 238)
      With John Dickinson. Last milestone on road to the Declaration of Independence.
      Includes John Dickinson 70 and Revolutionary War 617
    - EXTRACT OF LETTER ON INDIAN CULTURE AND EXPLORATION AND SCIENCE AND ART, Massachusetts Gazette, August 28, 1787 (Item 239)
    - EXTRACT OF LETTER ON INDIAN CULTURE AND EXPLORATION AND SCIENCE AND ART, American Museum Magazine, November 1787; Size: Small (Item 240)
    - ALBEMARLE LETTER, Gazette of United States, March 24, 1790 (Item 241)
      One of his most famous.
    - REPORT AS SECRETARY OF STATE ON COD AND WHALE FISHERIES, American Daily Advertiser, February 22, 1791 (Item 242)
    - LETTER TO FRENCH NATIONAL ASSEMBLY, Massachusetts Spy, December 15, 1791 (Item 243)
      Responding to their tribute to deceased Franklin, shows split in Washington cabinet and country between pro-French Jeffersonians and pro-British Federalists.
    - REPORT AS SECRETARY OF STATE ON NORTHWEST TERRITORY, Gazette of the United States, December 17, 1791 (Item 244)
    - JEFFERSON/BENJAMIN BANNEKER CORRESPONDENCE, Columbian Magazine, October 1792; Size: Small (Item 245)
    - LETTER TO FRENCH MINISTER, Gazette of the United States, July 20, 1793 (Item 246)
    - LETTERS ON GENET AND HIS LETTER, Concord Herald, September 5, 1793 (Item 247)
    - LETTERS ON GENET AND HIS LETTER, American Daily Advertiser, December 27, 1793 (Item 248)
    - LETTER TO MAZZEI EXCORIATING THE FEDERALIST GOVERNMENT AND PRECIPITATING THE FINAL RUPTURE WITH WASHINGTON, Columbian Centinel, May 10, 1797 (Item 249)
      Most notorious missive of Jefferson's career.
    - LETTER ON VIRTUES OF REPUBLICANISM, Massachusetts Spy, February 18, 1801 (Item 250)
    - LETTER TO HOUSE ACCEPTING ELECTION AS PRESIDENT, Connecticut Courant, March 9, 1801 (Item 251)
    - LETTER TO SWEDENBORGIAN CHURCH, Columbian Centinel, March 28, 1801 (Item 254)
    - LETTER TO PROVIDENCE CITIZENS ON ELECTIVE GOVERNMENT, THE CONSTITUTION, THE IMPROVEMENT OF MAN, THE WASTEFUL ENERGIES OF WAR, AND THE HOPE FOR PEACE WITH ALL NATIONS, The Massachusetts Spy, April 22, 1801 (Item 1061)
    - LETTER AFTER 1800 ELECTION, Telegraph and Daily Advertiser, April 30, 1801 (Item 255)
    - EXTRACT OF A LETTER WHERE JEFFERSON SPEAKS AGAINST THE SLANDERS OF HIS ENEMIES AND REGARDS HIMSELF AS THE SINCEREST FRIEND OF SCIENCE, New England Palladium, July 3, 1801 (Item 1028)
    - LETTER TO ELIJAH BROWN ON THE PERILS OF A FREE PRESS BUT THE NEED TO DEFEND IT, American Mercury, September 17, 1801 (Item 1062)
      Jefferson unusually in this kind of letter vents against the hated Federalists whose "distortions and perversions of truth and justice" and the "lacerations of its slanders" still compel us to willingly if reluctantly submit to maintain our freedom.
    - LETTER ON THE CONSTITUTION, New England Palladium, January 5, 1802 (Item 256)
    - LETTER TO CHESHIRE BAPTISTS ON THE CONSTITUTION AND VIRTUES OF BEING A FREEBORN FARMER, The Portfolio, January 23, 1802; Size: Small (Item 257)
    - LETTER ON BERCEAU AFFAIR, The Balance, May 25, 1802; Size: Small (Item 258)
    - PRE-SALLY SATIRICAL POEM THAT FIRST MENTIONS JEFFERSON'S SEXUAL RELATIONSHIP WITH SLAVES AND CALLENDER LETTER, The Portfolio, July 10, 1802; Size: Small (Item 259)
    - PRE-SALLY SATIRICAL POEM THAT FIRST MENTIONS JEFFERSON'S SEXUAL RELATIONSHIP WITH SLAVES AND CALLENDER LETTER, Farmer's Museum, August 10, 1802 (Item 260)
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 324 and Napoleon Bonaparte 895
    - JAMES CALLENDER'S ARTICLE EXPOSING JEFFERSON AND SALLY HEMINGS, New York Evening Post, September 10, 1802 (Item 263)
      First mention of Sally Hemings and one of the most scandalous articles in American history.
    - JAMES CALLENDER'S ARTICLE EXPOSING JEFFERSON AND SALLY HEMINGS, Farmer's Museum, September 28, 1802 (Item 265)
    - REFERENCES TO SALLY HEMINGS, New York Herald, September 25, 1802 (Item 264)
      Includes Toussaint Louverture 434, Anti-Jefferson 332, Anti-Jefferson 333
    - SATIRICAL POEM ON JEFFERSON AND SALLY HEMINGS, The Portfolio, October 2, 1802; Size: Small (Item 266)
      2 copies. Also in bound volume, The Portfolio, 1802-1803
    - SATIRICAL POEM ON JEFFERSON AND SALLY, The Portfolio, November 6, 1802; Size: Small (Item 272)
      See: bound volume, The Portfolio, 1802-1803
    - REFERENCES TO SALLY HEMINGS, The Portfolio, January 1, 15, 22, 1803; Size: Small (Item 277)
    - SATIRICAL POEM ON JEFFERSON AND SALLY (by J.Q. Adams), Boston Gazette, December 27, 1802 (Item 274)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 273
    - SATIRICAL POEM ON JEFFERSON, The Portfolio, January 22, 1803; Size: Small (Item 280)
    - SATIRICAL POEM ON JEFFERSON, SALLY AND PAINE, The Portfolio, April 9, 1803; Size: Small (Item 281)
    - LETTER TO PAINE ON HIS CONTROVERSIAL RETURN TO THE U.S., New York Herald, August 11, 1802 (Item 261)
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 325
    - LETTER TO PAINE ON HIS CONTROVERSIAL RETURN TO THE U.S., New England Palladium, August 13, 1802 (Item 262)
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 326
    - LETTERS TO JAMES CALLENDER, New York Evening Post, October 11, 1802 (Item 267)
      Implicating Jefferson in a possible corruption scandal involving Callender's attacks on Adams and Washington.
    - LETTERS TO JAMES CALLENDER, New York Herald, October 13, 1802 (Item 268)
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 345, Anti-Jefferson 340, Anti-Paine 521, and Toussaint Louverture 438
    - LETTERS TO JAMES CALLENDER, Massachusetts Spy, October 20, 1802 (Item 269)
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 350 and Toussaint Louverture 440
    - LETTERS TO JAMES CALLENDER, Farmer's Museum, October 26, 1802 (Item 270)
      Includes Anti-Jefferson 353
    - LETTERS TO JAMES CALLENDER, Balance, October 26, 1802; Size: Small (Item 271)
      See: Anti-Jefferson 352
    - COLUMN ON JEFFERSON AND CALLENDER LETTERS, REPORTS FROM LISBON, TANGIER, AND TRIPOLI DURING THE FIRST BARBARY WAR, New York Herald, October 23, 1802 (Item 963)
    - LETTER ON SPAIN VIOLATING LOUISIANA TREATY, The Balance, January 4, 1803; Size: Small (Item 278)
      Includes Jefferson 279 and Louisiana Territory and Purchase 648
    - MESSAGE AND EXTRACTS OF PAINE LETTER TO CITIZENS OF THE U.S., The Balance, January 4, 1803; Size: Small (Item 279)
      See: Thomas Jefferson 278
    - LETTER TO PAINE ON HIS CONTROVERSIAL RETURN TO THE U.S., The Balance, May 24, 1803; Size: Small (Item 282)
    - MESSAGE ON LOUISIANA, The Balance, November 8, 1803; Size: Small (Item 284)
    - MESSAGE ON OFFICIAL ACQUISITION OF LOUISIANA, Columbian Centinel, January 28, 1804 (Item 285)
    - LETTER TO CONGRESS ON TRIPOLITAN WAR (SEE SECTION BARBARY PIRATES), Massachusetts Spy, February 5, 1806 (Item 1063)
      This deals with the application of Hamet Karamanli, former Bashaw of Tripoli, to be restored to the throne now occupied by his brother. Six months previously, a force of eight US Marines and hundreds of mercenaries had captured Derna, leading to the end of the war. This was the first time the American flag was raised in victory on foreign soil (memorialized in the Marines Hymn, "the shores of Tripoli"). Wearied of the blockade and raids, and attempts to restore his brother to the throne, Yusuf Karamanli signed a peace treaty in June 1805. In agreeing to pay a ransom of $60,000 for the American prisoners, the Jefferson administration drew a distinction between paying tribute and paying ransom.
      Also JEFFERSON LETTER ON COMMERCE WITH ST. DOMINGO (HAITI)
    - REPORT FROM THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY ON THE AMOUNT OF DEPOSITS OF THE PUBLIC MONEY IN THE UNITED STATES AND OTHER BANKS FOR THE LAST THREE YEARS, BILL PROPOSING TO SURVEY THE COAST OF THE UNITED STATES, New York Herald, January 14, 1807 (Item 965)
    - CONGRESS DISCUSSION ON SALT TAX, REPORT ON MONEY APPROPRIATED FOR THE PRESIDENT TO IMPROVE AND REPAIR FORTIFICATIONS AND BUILD NEW GUNBOATS, New York Herald, January 21, 1807 (Item 966)
    - MESSAGE TO CONGRESS ON BURR CONSPIRACY, National Aegis, February 4, 1807 (Item 292)
      See: Aaron Burr 60
    - STATEMENT BY JOHN LANSING JR. (CHANCELLOR OF NEW YORK) AGAINST GOVERNOR DEWITT CLINTON AND JUDGE AMBROSE SPENCER, New York Herald, May 23, 1807 (Item 967)
    - PROCLAMATION INTERDICTING BRITISH VESSELS, November 19, 1807; Size: Small (Item 968)
    - MESSAGE TO CONGRESS ON EMBARGO, December 22, 1807; Size: Small (Item 970)
    - LETTERS TO CONGRESS AND NEW JERSEY LEGISLATURE AND EMBARGO ACT, Columbian Centinel, December 30, 1807 (Item 295)
    - MESSAGE TO CONGRESS JUSTIFYING EMBARGO, National Intelligencer, March 18, 1808 (Item 296)
    - PROCLAMATION ON EMBARGO, National Intelligencer, May 13, 1808 (Item 297)
      New England conspiring and trading with Canadians to avoid effects of Jefferson's embargo.
    - JEFFERSON ON THE EMBARGO, National Intelligencer, September 14, 1808 (Item 298)
    - LETTER EXPLAINING AND JUSTIFYING THE EMBARGO, National Intelligencer, September 28, 1808 (Item 999)
    - LETTERS ABOUT THE FRIENDSHIP OF JEFFERSON, MADISON AND MONROE AND WHO WILL SUCCEED JEFFERSON, American Citizen, November 2, 1808 (Item 299)
      Includes James Monroe 474
    - JEFFERSON ON EMBARGO DURING 1808 PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION, New York Herald, November 15, 1808 (Item 975)
    - MESSAGE TO CONGRESS ON EMBARGO, November 30, 1808; Size: Small (Item 977)
      Issued in consequence of the opposition, in the neighborhood of Lake Champlain, to the laws laying down an embargo.
    - JEFFERSON ON THE EMBARGO, Boston Gazette, December 22, 1808 (Item 301)